We talked about evolution.
我們講過生物演進理論。
Today we can actually see it.
今天我們真的可以看到了。
Today's research in the development of life,
近期生物進化史研究，
is a meeting of revolutionary new technologies
是結合革命性新科技
and old issues,
與舊論述，
because when genetic scientists looked closely
因為當基因科學家仔細研究
at our genes and DNA
我們的基因及DNA
we are starting to see it in the light of evolution
有嶄新的新發現
the classic issues that are starting to get answered with
透過基因工程我們可了解生物彼此的關係，
the help of genetic engineering is who is related to whom.
解釋了我們長久以來對生物演進的論述
We wish to label everything.
我們希望能註記所有連結。
We can see that deep down,
我們可以深入的說鯨魚是
a whale is a swimming camel.
會游泳的駱駝。
It's not obvious when you see it,
這當然不適顯而易見的，
but we have been forced
但當我們將
to move about a lot of branches on the tree of life.
生命樹上各分支分類後。
''Furgus''
"腐爛"
Hello?
哈囉?
Hey, it's me.
喂，是我。
How are you doing?
你最近如何?
Ok.
還好。
How was it?
怎麼樣?
Well, how did it go?
到底怎麼樣?
I'm gonna die.
我要死了。
Come on...
拜託...
He won't see me anymore.
我們很久沒有碰面了
What?
什麼?
Well, it's...
因為...
First, he said that he didn't have enough time.
第一，他說他沒有時間。
Then he said that there wasn't enough time.
接著他說沒有足夠的時間。
Then, he said that he's in love with another.
接著他說他跟別人相戀了
He has been seeing her all this time.
他在這段期間一直跟她在一起
That sounds totally crazy!
這說法真瘋狂!
What a fucking asshole.
真是該死的渾蛋。
Well, now they have cut down my hours,
且，他們現在縮減我的工作時數，
which is not fun at all
一點都不好玩
I think he has given me a fucking venerial disease.
我想他傳染給我該死的性病。
Come on...
拜託...
I will die.
我會死。
You will not die.
你不會死。
Yes!會!
No!不會!
Yes, it itches like hell and I will die!
會，它像地獄般的癢!
No!
不會!
No, but you've probably got fungus.
不會，可能只是黴菌感染
I've had it and it's disgusting! It itches.
我應該得到了而且好噁心!好癢。
You can just get some stuff from the pharmacy.
你可以去藥局買些東西。
I think I have some left. And then...
我想我應該還有一些剩下。然後...
Wait.
等一下。
Has she gone mad?
她發瘋了嗎?
Who?
誰?
The old lady in number nine!
住九號的老女人!
What's she doing?
她在幹嘛?
She's like a hundred years old
他像一百多歲的老人，
and now she's standing completely fucking naked,
她現在該死的全裸，
just screaming!
不停的尖叫!
Nude? Are you kidding?
全裸?你開玩笑吧?
No, I'm not.
不，我沒開玩笑。
That's sick!
那好病態!
What's she doing now?
她現在在幹嘛?
Tell me!
跟我說!
What's she doing?
她在幹嘛?
This is so weird.
超怪的。
Well, now they've cut down my hours
恩，他們現在縮減
and that doesn't feel good at all.
我的小時數讓人感到不舒服。
I'm gonna die! He's given me shit.
我要死了!他給我這爛東西
Cut it out. You've got fungus.
停止。你只是黴菌感染。
You just have to buy...
你只需要買...
What's that?
那是什麼?
Wait.
等下。
Hello?
哈囉?
It's me. Can you let me in?
是我。妳可以讓我進去嗎?
I'm just gonna grab my stuff,
我只是要拿我的東西，
the jacket and the pan. I' ll be fast.
夾克及平底鍋。我會很快。
Hello?
哈囉?
Katrin?
克莉絲汀?
Hello, hello, hello, hello?
哈囉，哈囉，哈囉，哈囉?
Hello? Hey, what's going on?
哈囉?嘿，怎麼了?
He's here.
他來了。
For fuck's sake.
該死的。
He's outside.
他在外面。
Don't let him in!
不要讓他進來!
Tell him that you're not at home.
跟他說你不在家。
He wants his stuff back.
他要拿回他的東西。
There's an itch between my legs
我的雙腿間很癢，
and he wants his stuff back.
但他要拿回他的東西。
Toss it out from the balcony or something.
從陽台或那裡丟出去。
Let me in, Katrin!
讓我進去，克莉絲汀!
I know you're there, you just answered!
我知道你在裡面，你剛有回應!
Hey, doesn't he owe you money?
嘿，他不是還欠你錢?
A thousand kronor.
一千克朗。
Did you get it back?
你有沒有拿回來?
I'm sorry. Hey, I'm really sorry.
我很抱歉，我真的很抱歉。
Last week he told me he loved me.
上星期他說他愛我。
I love him, you know.
我愛他，你知道嗎?
No, I don't get it at all.
不，我完全不了解。
My jacket and pan.
我的夾克跟平底鍋。
Is it itching?
還在癢嗎?
Like hell.
像地獄。
Yeah, well...
是的,嗯...
Katrin?
克莉絲汀?
What the hell is she doing?
她到底在幹嘛?
Katrin?
克莉絲汀?
Hello?
哈囉?
Hello, hello, hello, hello?
哈囉，哈囉，哈囉，哈囉?
Answer me!
回答我!
Katrin?
克莉絲汀?
I'm hanging up now.
我要掛電話了
Katrin, I'm hanging up now.
克莉絲汀，我要掛電話了
Hello?
哈囉?
I'm hanging up now.
我要掛電話了
Hello?
哈囉?
Hello!
哈囉!
Where the hell did you go?
你到底跑到哪裡了?
I won't get my money back.
我的錢要不回來了。
Well, just tell him that you want it back.
嗯，跟他說還你錢。
I have to go.
我不能多說了。
Come on now. It's only fungus.
拜託。只是黴菌感染。
You're not going to die.
你不會死的。
Just buy one of those ointments.
只需要買些軟膏。
Perhaps.
應該。
Anyway.
無論如何。
I have another meeting with my boss.
我現在另外要跟我老闆開會。
You know, I've been working there for five years...
你知道的，我在那裡工作五年了...
the whales. Both whales and dolphins belong to a
鯨魚。根據生命樹，
branch that goes out from the tree of life.
鯨魚跟海豚來自同個分支。
So, we follow it back so that
所以，根據推斷，
we can see where it meets other animals.
我們可連結其他動物。
Which animals are similar to whales?
那種動物相似
Then we enter into what we call the ungulates.
我們歸類有蹄動物。
This includes, for example,cows, pigs and camels.
包含，舉例來說，牛，豬跟駱駝。
Among all the other animals,
在所有其他的動物來說，
whales are the closest...
鯨魚類似...